Hey English learners, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. In
today's video, I'm going to talk about
soft skills. Soft skills are the skills
that we have that aren't technical,
right? uh in particular today I want to
talk about soft skills related to
communication
and how you can use these skills these
soft skills to improve your
communication
and of course when you speak English
when you speak a foreign language it's
good to have these skills they'll make
your communication
better and more effective in any
language that you speak. So, that's what
we're going to talk about today. And
remember to check out my listening
practice seminars. You can join my
membership and get access to those
seminars to help you understand when
native speakers speak fast. Okay, I know
that a lot of you have trouble
understanding fast English and that's
why I have those seminars to help you
train and help you uh understand
different patterns that can be hard to
understand when people speak fast. And
also, if you want to start speaking and
you need a teacher, then I highly
recommend that you check out my US
Conversations podcast because in that
podcast, I talk to many different
English teachers from around the US. And
so you can uh hear uh and listen to my
conversations with those teachers and
see if you like them and take a class
with one of them. So those links are
down below. Okay, let's talk about soft
skills. So uh as I already mentioned
soft skills are the skills that we have
that aren't technical. So both soft
skills and hard skills are important uh
in some fields. Hard skills are more
important than soft skills. But in some
fields, soft skills might be equally as
important or even more important than
hard skills. And for me, in my
experience,
uh I don't have a lot of hard skills.
Okay? I don't have a lot of technical
skills uh except for um skills related
to language, writing, linguistics,
things like that. Uh but I do have uh
some soft skills that have helped me
develop my career. uh specifically my
way of communicating,
my way of speaking. Um these skills have
helped me uh make content for English
learners and uh people uh tend to like
my way of talking, the way I speak. And
so these aren't technical skills, these
are soft skills, but they have been
really important for me in my career.
And I think that soft skills related to
communication are really important. and
you are a language learner and so you
should uh care about communicating well
and having uh good uh soft skills that
can help you when you interact with
other people in English or in any other
language. So let me talk about some
specific soft skills related to
communication that can really help you.
So number one is adjusting your speech
to different audiences.
So many people uh lack this skill. they
aren't able to change the way that they
speak depending on who is listening to
them. And I think most people could
improve in this area. I've seen uh many
instances where an English speaker is
talking to someone who doesn't speak
English well, but the English speaker
doesn't change the way that they speak
to help the other person understand
them. They just talk really fast and use
complicated phrases and idioms and
things like that and they aren't able to
adjust the way that they speak so that
the person listening to them can
understand better. And this isn't just
for talking to people who don't speak
your language well. Uh we talk
differently to adults, to kids,
teenagers,
people who are a lot older than us,
people who we need to show a lot of
respect towards. uh there are different
ways to talk to different people and we
need to use the appropriate language and
tone and formality
depending on our audience. So this is an
important soft skill to have because it
will allow you to communicate in the
proper way to different people.
And that is something that we want to be
able to do. Another soft skill related
to communication is being able to read
other people. Meaning you can see the
other person and feel how they are
feeling and you can imagine how they
might be uh thinking.
um uh how comfortable they are, uh
things like that. You want to be able to
tell when a person is uncomfortable,
when they're uneasy, like they don't
feel uh very good, uh or maybe if
they're uninterested
in what you're saying, uh or if they're
not understanding what you're saying.
It's important to be able to identify
this uh so that you can adjust the way
that uh you're talking uh so that the
other person responds better. Right? I
think that's an important soft skill to
have. uh it can help you keep the other
person engaged and comfortable with the
conversation, right? Uh another soft
skill that's really important is being
able to listen well. Be a good listener,
right? We want to listen to other people
with interest. We want to be genuinely
interested in what other people are
saying. When you show a genuine
interest, people can feel that. People
see that and it makes them feel more
comfortable around you. It makes them
want to talk to you. So, that's good.
And it's good to show that you're
listening, right? You nod. You use some
affirmations like yes. Uh-huh. You uh
show the other person that you're
listening. That's important. Uh it's
good to react to what the other person
is saying. It shows that you're
listening when you have a genuine
reaction when they say different things.
Um, it's good to ask questions about
things that they say. All of these
things are part of being a good listener
and they will help you have better
interactions with people. It's also a
good thing to be able to create a
comfortable atmosphere. That's a good
soft skill. Smile and laugh. That's
important. Add humor when it's
appropriate. Uh people like to laugh.
They like humor. If you can add this
naturally to the interaction, that can
really help. It makes the other person
uh feel better when talking to you.
They're more interested in talking to
you probably. Um, and you want to make
the other person feel comfortable
uh sharing their opinions,
uh, talking about their feelings, uh,
sharing stories with you. Uh, you want
to create a comfortable atmosphere so
that the other person feels comfortable
to do those things, right? And one other
soft skill that is important to have is
to be concise. Meaning you can
communicate
something effectively
without using too many words. Okay. Um
it's okay to talk and use a lot of
words. That's not bad. But when we're
trying to communicate important ideas,
it's important to be able to do so in a
concise way to really help them
understand the point. Um, I've had this
experience before where I'm in a group
of people and one person starts uh
telling a story and they're not being
concise and it's hard to understand what
the point of the story is until the very
end after they've talked for a long
time. And I can see that the other
people are kind of losing interest and
they don't get the point of what is
being said because the other person
who's telling the story isn't being
concise. they aren't able to effectively
communicate the message uh in a concise
way and that causes other people to lose
interest or they stop paying attention
or they just wonder h why is he telling
this story? So being concise is an
important soft skill to have. There are
many other soft skills that are
important, but those are the ones I
wanted to talk about today. Hopefully,
uh, this video got you thinking about
how you can improve in these areas so
that you can have better interactions in
English or in your native language. So,
uh, I hope you enjoyed this video.
Remember to check out my listening
practice seminars by becoming a
listening time family member so uh you
can train your listening with me and
start to understand better when people
speak fast. And check out my US
Conversations podcast so you can
practice listening to my conversations
that I have with other English teachers.
So, uh, that's a great resource for your
listening and you can also use it to
find an English teacher to take classes
online with. So, those links are down
below. Thank you all for listening to
this A2 English listening practice video
and I'll talk to you in the next